[music]
Hi Lisa, how are you today?
>> I'm great. I'm excited to be at Google
Plex. Yes, it's a crazy days in AI as
you know from your perspective as an
investment and to figuring out what is
the best way not best way what is the
best area to invest in in space of AI so
many what what you have in mind and
first of all if you would be able to
introduce yourself
>> yeah absolutely so uh Lisa Dolan a
longtime partner with link ventures and
partner of John Warders who has put on
these events I uh really initially has
focused on MIT Harvard as link is across
the street from MIT in Kendall Square uh
and now expanding to other technical
schools. So over the
>> Boston area or
>> well over my career I have found that
MIT Harvard is one area of uh the talent
ecosystem but there's other incredible
ecosystems nationwide also
internationally but I'm focused only on
the US where they have an unfair
understanding of a given uh industry to
disrupt and so when we talk about where
AI can be applied if you're investing in
carne Melon they are tremendous at
robotics when you're investing in uh
Georgia Tech they're also strong at
robotics at Duke Johns Hopkins which was
my alma mo Johns Hopkins strong in
healthcare so basically the strategy
that I'm executing is to have exposure
to these what I'll call talent
ecosystems that are budding to very
antiquated industries and those those
students have an unfair advantage to
disrupt that industy
So you can't only invest in Stanford,
you need to invest in other ecosystems
to get exposure to those industries.
>> Yes, Roman Nemed here. [clears throat]
I'm also working with John Wernner
putting all these great events together
and funny enough as you're saying I do
some research in that space what to
invest into and starting with uh as you
said where the talent is but what to
invest into in the sense what will be
useful to humanity and AI as we know or
we think it can help. So what in your
thinking what would be the areas to
invest the AI can help to humanity or
local problems to be solved?
>> Yeah. So uh if we just look at my newest
investments latest investments I'm
investing in AI applied to
biocommercialization.
So uh not shy so not on the discovery
side but on um the commercialization
manufacturing side. uh great MIT team.
I'm also investing in AI applied to
uh actually mining uh oil and gas and
mining. And this is a robotics company
out of MIT and uh they are basically
automating the crushing of rocks, right,
which is a very human uh monitored
industry that um uh is now going to be
disrupted. They're working with folks
like cement builders, H Highleberg, um,
and Caterpillar. Uh, so very very sort
of I would call it non-sexy and
antiquated industries. Then, uh, another
investment of mine recently is AI
applied to uh, logistics and freight.
>> Yes.
>> So again, another great industry and
then insurance. So what's interesting
about all the companies that I'm seeing
today is that their business model will
be different today than they will be in
a year and in two years. Insurance is
this beautiful uh call it uh Trojan
horse opportunity for revenue. When you
have better structured and unstructured
data, the clear opportunity is better
basically not only uh better pricing of
risk premiums um but a better
understanding of the um the credit score
of every consumer in that ecosystem. And
so investing in an insurance product
that will essentially be a product for
the full portfolio. So it's a broad
spectrum of many things, logistics,
mining,
engineering and
bio and all that. It's a kind of large
space large space or different spaces
rather. So how do you see AI for example
in mining? You said antiquated
as a as a process to dig something out
of ground but we do know there's a lot
of minerals we do need like for
batteries or chips. So you're
specializing on these kind of type of
materials or just any in terms of
processing or mining on
>> Yeah. Uh there's another company
invested in Carnegie Melon guys that are
Cing Mel and Stanford that are doing
rare earth processing. So literally
taking the copper and gold that lives in
all of our modems and processing that
for actually could be jewelry and that
is really in the trend of having
onshoring of um processing of a rare
earth and so you'll see this trend in my
portfolio is yes I will invest in AI for
perhaps you know legal and accountancy
but that's not my focus is really uh
unless you're the category winner there
Um I'm really focused on the dirty
industries. Uh one of my biggest wins
was investing in Merkore at Seed uh now
$20 billion uh company. Um Georgetown
Harvard uh team and uh they are uh
really informing helping inform where I
allocate uh capital because they are the
largest recruiters for OpenAI, Nvidia,
Meta uh and they are responsible for
labeling those models. they're also
going into the physical world and
physical AI and real world data labeling
and so I work with communicate with them
as to what they are uh looking at next
as an opportunity to where I want to be
investing in in this
>> question how how you find out how you
landed on these different areas to
invest bio logistic and such I was
assumed that you did some research
around that in my space what I my
thinking is what we humans need to solve
the problems. AI can can may help us or
may not may bankrupt us completely. How
how did you be came about or did you do
your research to focus on these areas?
What was the the reasoning around it?
>> Yeah. So as I mentioned uh links focus
is really MIT Harvard which has been my
focus. Um but uh I was a John's Hopkins
undergrad. Uh so for different schools
you'll have areas of specialty. So when
I'm looking at healthcare I'll look at
Duke, Johns Hopkins, MIT um when I'm
looking at robotics uh Carnegi Melon.
And so I have established a network of
uh of sorcerers uh that can help me get
exposure to all those those uh
industries. um you know mining actually
Alberta and Canada has a lot um of
talent there um and so that's my
structure of having uh basically a
national grid so that you can get
exposure to these these antiquated
industries um but um yeah if I could
tell you how many like chat bots I've
seen for um for for lawyers and
accountants and and private equity guys
um it's just a really it's a it's a
really hard uh industry to build a
category.
>> We humans over the time created these
monstrous processes and organization and
governance of many things. So I see as a
good match you're looking around the
academia with fuel how we can extract
certain minerals and then matching it
with logistic or location where those
are there already might be some
technologies how to extract at least
dirt but how to find where those
minerals might be and then figure out
who owns the lands and all this whole
process from not just how technically
speaking but there's a lot of other
things besides investments you need to
find a permitting you need to find the
the landlords and all sorts of other
things. So, it's kind of machinery of
many things. So, I would assume you have
uh helpers or some views or some
information gathering what and why not
to and as you mentioned before the
camera was on it might be political. So,
it's kind of a lot of things in mixed
bag of many things to sort out and then
figure out eventually is that worth to
invest.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well um in terms of the
resources that I have for founders is
really around um I can't say this word
more um enough is distribution. I have
found that distribution distribution
distribution and sales is really uh the
key winner of what I've seen of my of my
uh strongest performers um example they
just really have an understanding and
what I would say practice unfair
nepotism. What unfair nepotism means is
um or artificial nepotism means getting
several stakeholders in a company uh
whether that be the CEO, the CTO, the BD
guy um and the engineer, customer
service person all to support you. Um,
and so when I'm investing, I'm really uh
helping our portfolio companies as an
example, the AI for mining company
actually helping them with uh finding uh
mines um and uh there's a company uh
just recently that we connected to uh
the mining company that is an Apollo
backed uh private equitybacked mine that
um has tremendous distribution. So
that's really the focus is is
distribution. Anything we can do to help
get some type of unfair early
distribution advantage.
>> Speaking of the mining, it's antiquated
as you said. You think of from your
knowledge, you already went out there.
Are they actually leveraging AI to
figuring out what to what to dig or or
analyze whatever the mines are, what
other minerals there might be? You know,
they are all coal mines. Is there any
other minerals possibly?
how they actually I'm just curious how
the mining industry at this time is
leveraging this if at all or they kind
of relying on academia or other
researchers maybe like yourself to
invest to kind of monitor what they can
do going forward. So, so this company
actually um their core insights uh three
MIT roboticists at core insight is
really in computer vision and being able
to see in the um the conditions of a
mine [clears throat] and uh we're all so
this is sort of we think about a
vertical company they're actually really
taking a horizontal uh approach of
having computer vision uh that is
optimized for a mine. They're initially
focusing on actually cement mines,
right? So that's their it's not gold,
it's not something flashy. It's actually
just cement. Um and there is a competing
company that is taking a vertical
approach. They're actually trying to be
the next uh AI or uh computer vision
cement manufacturing company. Um and so
they're taking it the horizontal
approach and basically selling into H
Highidleberg um which is one of the
largest national cement manufacturers uh
selling into Caterpillar. Um
>> there's all the process business
>> right and so they're they're capital
light versus being sort of a vertical uh
a vertically integrated company. Um but
uh there there two approaches to it and
I'm sort of taking the um the capital
light approach. I what I do like the
combination you have the mining say and
logistics cuz you have the dirt or the
ore and you need to distribute it
somewhere. Logistics supply chain is
another large area in general for AI and
robotics as well. So we are here in the
San Francisco area has a lot of robotics
companies. So you are looking for
finding some in terms of logistics or
supply.
>> Yeah. So one part of the logistics point
is what I do is sort of have a core
insight around where I think AI can be
applied and then print it out. So the
logistics company believe it or not is
is is
identifying freight fraud uh and errors
and so clearly AI is a great applica
opportunity to verify drivers. Uh so
what this company is doing is simply
having uh optimized verification of of
drivers of freight drivers and from
there they can offer payments and they
can offer better warranty of what is
being shipped. Um but their core insight
is actually verification.
Um and so that uh also can pertain to
medicine, right? verifying who's a
better surgeon than than the other by
matching uh surgery screens visuals of
surgery screens with outcomes and so
that's sort of the process of how I make
investments across ver vertical is
saying okay what's the core insight uh
verification actually can be applied to
logistics to uh to medicine to xyz
industry um so it's just it's an
understanding of how the process works
Yeah, great. Thank you. What I would
ask, what do you kind of foresee? What
are we larger obstacles than all your
industries? I'm sure different industry,
different obstacle, geo politics being
one large of them. What my view is, you
know, all of this for humanity, but
there's a lot of roadblocks, not
necessarily AI, not necessarily what is
in the dirt we need to extract for our
our our
benefit as a humanities. what you would
see the larger obstacle in is the
technology, is that the people, is that
the politics if you will, is that some
other obstacles you might see and the
follow would be how we would possibly
remove these roadblocks.
So I think that uh privacy risk
regulation are all you know underpriced
in the market um in terms of the ai
valuations is there will have to be uh
better regulations there's going to have
to be better uh risk you know controls
you know when there was the uh data
breach at Merkore and everybody was so
worried I I was like this is this is
this is a a pin prick of what we're
going to have in terms of data breaches
So I think that that is um everybody
knows it's going to happen but I think
it's really hard to to price um and you
can't as an investor. I I think it's
really hard to
>> so those are these risks I guess you
have to consider and hope hope for the
best or navigate to kind of avoid all
these obstacles and possible threats
>> right and I think that's clearly a
vertical that people will invest in um
is uh everything around risk controls um
in a given um AI application or
>> yeah plenty of these AI applications and
it's also hard to navigate in this kind
of event like we have today or this
days. It's a good opportunity to figure
out what that direction might be. You
might have been to the first. I kind of
like the interaction between Daniel
Larus and Alex.
>> Yeah.
>> Kind of back and forth. What might be? I
do know Alex is a little, you know,
futuristic. Put it that way. I'm by hard
or trade engineer. So, it's more
practical. So how to merge this uh the
futuristic ideas with the practicalities
and what I see what you're doing is more
the practical part how we can help
ourselves using AI to extract mining or
to have our lives easier going forward.
Well, I think as a venture investor, you
need to uh have um Alex's uh uh and he
was the long-term, you know, advisor at
Link as uh they have his perspective. Um
while uh and I would say I actually
identify this as as some of the
attributes of my best founders is they
have this unfair unique uh vision of the
future but also they are the best at
being reactive to real time market
changes. Um, and you can't only be
thinking about the future. You need to
be really, really great at those real
time market changes, making the hard
choices. And that's the difference when
you're an operator versus,
>> you know, um, on on sort of [laughter]
>> right on the hill there. But we do I
kind of agree that we need some
visionaries. They may see what we
wrangler folks don't and kind of go
towards if that happens. We'll see.
>> Yeah. I mean, I think the business model
conversation of, you know, how business
models are going to change with AI. I
still see my companies struggle to
change how they're going to have their
uh, you know, a nonsoftware license uh,
you know, per seat model. Like it's
still um, uh, just tried and true in
terms of how the buyer um buyer uh,
behaves. But that's the reason I think
that payments is so interesting and
insurance is so interesting. Um just so
that's more of a transactionbased
um model that can be organic but it's
really I've I've seen I've seen friction
in terms of getting beyond that per se.
>> Money moves the world as they say.
So thank you for discussion of this and
I think
that's the good practical way to go
about this hopefully we you know you
bring it up there and one last question
where is your
compared to like Alex your crystal ball
what might be in your space that is
coming for next 5 10 years where we
might be with say insurance how they
would change or the mining how they
would possibly change it supply chain
and bio kind of zooming on more the bio
we haven't touched on that if you have
some ideas for where that might be
going. Um well I think the bio I think
bio application is one of the most
exciting uh and unfortunately I see a
lot of you know AI for social media and
how to like you know automate your
LinkedIn posting um because those are
the easy um you know the easy um
opportunities but the ones that are
really uh just incredible and what keep
me up at night is the bio applications
and I think again there's going to have
to be a lot of um uh risk controls
around that because with every good you
can also have have bad. Um but I see the
opportunity with AI bio actually again
on the manufacturing and
commercialization side being able to
generate uh molecules uh instantly and
just small small changes and
personalized medicine where the actual
think dollars are. Yes, maybe they'll
flow to Chashi BT, but they won't. I
think they're really going to flow to
somebody who has the opportunity to get
a part of that um of that added uh added
production, right? Um so super excited
for personalized medicine. Um and so the
one that I invested in is called LRA
Labs. Uh little [laughter]
>> um it's it's still under in stealth. um
Menlo ventures led it and is is focused
in bio um commercialization. kind of
interested from you discussing with all
the different people how AI is where is
the AI on their radar like CEO or say
mining or supply chain is there what I
my mini research many of the CEOs still
don't necessarily fully comprehend what
the AI value is to their business and
they still operate in this older
traditionally feel way of thinking the
large companies perhaps they have their
people they want it but they medium to
small they are kind of way behind with
this. I don't know if you experience
similar kind of
>> um well what I'm seeing is uh when a
startup is trying to sell into either
the enterprise or the midmarket um
they're they're now actually more and
more interested in the mid-market
because uh the enterprise has the build
verse buy decision and they can build it
in house and so um the midmarket has
become this new um area of focus. I
think the jury is still out on it. Um,
frankly, but um the I've seen a lot of
one of my companies that is um AI to
construction is trying to sell into uh
sort of the the mid-market, not the not
the uh the big guys.
>> Big guys. Yes, I agree. I mean following
how AI works the decentralization like
agenting AI the smaller pockets they
still amount to a lot rather than
dictate if you will for the larger
companies what we as a humanity should
do they might not capture everything
they might don't want to so the medium
companies kind of filling the gap for us
humanity fuel to build better lives for
us I would absolutely agree and
we should like in the in in the
investments going forward and I'm sure
there is many many opportunities even in
the audience here you meet people and uh
going forward and last question is uh
for your
you are trying to invest or investing
like immediate the outputs if you will
or more longer term five years where you
see the the results coming back to in
your investment
>> so I I'm a seed investor seed in series
A um [clears throat] the strategy is um
more times at bat. So um in terms of the
funds construction so I want to make
more investments um in the seed and have
less for followons. But what I've seen
is that there's a bigger difference
today between the halves and have nots.
So put larger checks into the companies
that um are are doing well but not have
the normal uh sort of uh venture
calculus of investing your prata in the
series A's. It's really those series B's
where you just see the difference
between the winners and the and the
losers. Um and so uh that sort of
structure of
>> how you deal with the you know
flexibility of dynam you know the AI is
evolving a huge speed of light if you
will and things are changing we
discovering kind of reinventing on the
go. So what you foresee today might look
completely different tomorrow. So is
there how you adjust if you will the
journeys you have with your investments?
>> Yeah, I think it's really about team and
distribution. I was saying you know
everybody's talking about Anthropic
today. There was a good like uh post
about their 80% gross margins which are
actually they're losing money. Um but uh
if you look at their numbers, it's uh
it's taking out uh partner uh you know
uh partner shared revenue and taking out
um stockbased compensation. So they're
losing money. Um but ultimately they're
going to have distribution. So I would
tell you that whatever their business
model is today is not going to be their
business model in in two years, 3 years
or 5 years. Um, and so I think that's,
you know, I'm uh I'm very bullish on on
Andrew as an example just just as the
point of the fact that whoever is going
to have um mass distribution today will
be able and and be able to hire the best
talent will be able to um um to roll the
punches and and pivot and pivot and
pivot. But um I as sort of going back to
what I initially said is those founders
that are really good at being reactive
to real-time market changes are going to
be the winners while also having that
long-term vision.
>> Yeah, the business models are changing
because of the all the time. And because
we are nearing the time, if you might
have a last words of wisdom in terms of
investment, how to go or advice?
>> Um yeah. Basically I would say uh think
for I think there's a lot of um oh like
VC has been always this industry but
think for yourself uh and do what others
are not doing. I think that's the
hardest thing to do right now is there's
such a strong strong uh and dialogue in
in AI. Uh it's really hard to zigg and
zag while others are are zagging and
zigging. So do something different and
think different. So
>> yeah, AI allows that. So thank you for
for the time and explaining or
discussing this awesome topic.
>> Awesome. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> [music]